opensourcevarsity.com 2012-03-30

# Privacy Policy - opensourcevarsity.com

## PRIVACY AND SECURITY 

The **O** pen **S** ource **V** arsity [ OSV ] recognizes the importance of maintaining your privacy. We value your privacy and appreciate your trust in us. 

This Privacy Policy applies to current and former visitors to our website and to our online customers. By visiting and/or using our website, you agree to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy explains the information practices that apply to personally identifiable information that we collect about you as an individual when you visit and/or use our website. 

Any information that we collect about you while you are visiting or using our website will be handled in accordance with this Opensourcevarsity.com Privacy Policy and will not be shared except in accordance with this privacy policy.

We strongly recommend you to review this Privacy Statement in its entirety.

The sole owner of all personal information collected at this site is the OpenSourceVarsity [OSV] and OSV will NEVER rent or sell your personal information, without your prior consent, except as otherwise set out herein. 

## CREDIT CARD SECURITY

OSV currently uses PayPal as our payment gateways to collect the payment for our products, which is 100% safe and secure. A customer needs to enter their credit card details on the PayPal payment page only. Kindly note OSV does not store any kind of credit card details of our customers.

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT:

This section of our Privacy Policy describes the categories of information collected by OSV. You have the option not to provide information; however, withholding information may prevent you from being able to use some of our website features.

Information Collected Automatically: Whenever you visit our website, we may automatically collect some information about your transactions with us, and your use of our website. For example, we automatically collect your IP address, for OSV’s internal use only, such as to help us diagnose problems with our server and administer our website. 

We also automatically track certain information about your activities on our website such as the type of web browser you are using and click stream data. If you are a registered OSV customer, we link this automatically-collected data to the personally identifiable information we collect about you described below. We use this information to do internal research on your interests and to help us better understand and serve you.

Information You Send To Us: If you choose to provide us with Personal Information, such as by sending us an e-mail or by filling out a form with your Personal Information and submitting it to us through our Website, we collect the Personal Information that you provide to us. For example, if you register or sign up for an account with us, we collect your name, e-mail address, telephone number and password. If you place an order with us, we collect the Personal Information that you provide to us such as your shipping, billing, and payment information.

## COOKIES AND SIMILAR FILES:

Our Website uses “cookies” and files that are similar to cookies. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers created by your browser at our request and stored in an approved and standardized place on your computer.

By transferring these cookies, OSV assigns you a unique customer code and record locater. Information about your activity on our Website can then be included in your customer record, which is stored within the OSV firewall. When you visit or return to our Website, we read the cookie to identify you as one of our customers and help recall orders or preferences you have selected. The cookie also enables us to recall your past activities, post your account data, and tailor site elements and special offers to you. No Personal Information about you is stored on the cookie.

Most Web browsers accept cookies by default, but allow users to reject cookies by changing the browser preferences. If you have set up your browser to reject cookies, some aspects of our Website, including our Shopping Cart, will not work properly.

This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies and similar files by Opensourcevarsity.com only and does not cover the use of cookies and similar files by any third party advertisers or websites linked to the Website.

In future, we may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may use a cookie or an action tag, also known as a Web Beacon or a 1 pixel .gif file, to track your response to their advertisement and to measure the effectiveness of their advertising or to award incentives or points to their members who respond to their advertisements. OSV has no access to or control over cookies or action tags used by these third party companies. OSV does not receive any personally identifiable information collected by these advertisers using action tags or cookies nor does OSV share any of your personally identifiable information such as your name, telephone number or address with these companies except in accordance with this privacy policy.

## USE AND DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION:

We use the information that we collect about you to maintain, improve, and administer our website, operate our business, provide products and services that you request, administer your account, inform you about products and services that might be of interest to you, and personalize your online experience.

In order to carry out certain business functions, such as order fulfillment, e-mail delivery, or marketing, we sometimes hire other companies to perform services on our behalf. We may disclose personally identifiable information that we collect about you to these companies to enable them to perform these services, but they are required to safeguard the data and are not authorized to use it for any other purpose than completing their contractual requirements to OSV. 

For example, as a part of the normal process of completing your purchase, OSV may provide your personal data to a third party payment processor, such as PayPal etc depending on your chosen method of payment. Please be aware that, because of the limitations of the systems used by some financial institutions, the statement you receive from your credit card or financial institution may show the name of a third party payment processor, instead of or in addition to the OSV name. 

In addition, we may share the information we collect with other companies with whom we have joint marketing arrangements.

We may also disclose information, including personal information; we collect about you in other circumstances as required or permitted by law. For example, OSV reserves the right to disclose Personal Information, including account information, when we believe such disclosure is appropriate to cooperate with an investigation of activities claimed to be unlawful, to enforce our Terms of Use, or to protect the rights or property of OSV or others. 

In addition, it is possible that in the future another company may acquire OSV or its assets. It is also possible that OSV may partner with or purchase another company to continue to do business as a combined entity. In the event that this occurs, it is possible that our customer information, including your Personal Information, may be transferred to the new business entity as one of OSV’s assets. In such an event, we will update this policy to reflect any change in ownership or control of your Personal Information.

## LINKS TO THIRD PARTY PRODUCTS AND SERVICES

In future conditions, while you are visiting or using the OSV website, you may be presented with an opportunity to purchase third party products or services. These products and services are offered and supplied by independent companies not owned or operated by OSV.

If you click on one of the presented offers, you will be redirected to the site of the third party, and any information you provide in response to the offer will be collected and used by the third party and not by OSV. Information you provide to the third party and any dealings you have with the third party will be governed by the privacy and other policies of that third party.

## YOUR CHOICES:

We offer you a variety of choices with respect to how we use and share your personal information.

Communications from OSV - If you do not want to receive communications from OSV about products and services that may be of interest to you, simply indicate this preference by logging into “My Account,” selecting “Account Update, and updating your preference. 

Even if you choose to be placed on one of these lists, we may still communicate with you using any of these methods regarding your use of our Website, your orders or your account.

Deactivation of Your Account - You may also request deactivation of your OSV account by contacting us and requesting account deactivation. Please note that some information may remain in our archived records after your account has been deactivated.

## HOW TO MANAGE YOUR ACCOUNT:

If you wish to change your name, e-mail address, telephone number, password, communication and/or opt-in preferences after you have registered, you can access your account by logging into My Account and selecting Account Update.

## WEBSITE SECURITY:

We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards designed to help us protect your nonpublic personal information. When you establish an account at OSV, you choose a password to help protect your account information. 

A password is only as strong as you make it. You should select a unique password and keep it safe. You may change the password as often as you wish by going to “My Account” and selecting "Account Update."

OSV authorizes only those persons who need to know personal information to administer your account, to provide or inform you about products and services, or to maintain, improve or administer our website to access your personal information.

Our sign-in process is designed to help protect your privacy. If you have trouble signing in to our website, please ensure that you are using your registered e-mail address and/or correct password. If you are using your registered e-mail address and correct password, and you continue to have trouble signing in to our site, please contact us immediately.

OSV sends an e-mail notice confirming acceptance of each order you place to the e-mail address you provided to us when signing up for OSV account. If you receive a confirmation for an order you did not place, please e-mail us immediately.

## YOUR RESPONSIBILITIES

We go to great lengths to protect all of your information on our Site. To help us maintain the security of your personal information, we ask that you do not share your password with anybody. Sharing this information could put you and your rating as a buyer/seller at risk. If you lose control of your password or you think that somebody has obtained unauthorized access to your account, immediately change your password.

## CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and as such do not target our website(s) to such children under the age of 13 years. However, our site may contain links to content providers that collect information from children under the age of 13. We have no control over such content providers and are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other web sites. It is stated for general information that Internet offers open access to a wide range of information; hence it is important that parents and guardians supervise and prevent their children’s access to inappropriate content, email or chat sessions.

## LEGAL DISCLAIMER

Though every effort is made to preserve your privacy, OSV may need to disclose personal information when required to by law. If it is deemed necessary that such action needs to be taken, OSV will comply with judicial proceedings should a court order or legal process be served on OSV.

## CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY 

Handcraft.co.in may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time by posting a revised Privacy Policy on our Website. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently.

## COMMENTS/QUESTIONS

Any questions concerning this Privacy Policy may be directed by e-mail to [admin](mailto:admin@opensourcevarsity.com)
